<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>会议论文 | 张杰的个人主页</title>
    <link>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication-type/%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%AE%E8%AE%BA%E6%96%87/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication-type/%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%AE%E8%AE%BA%E6%96%87/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>会议论文</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jackaugust.github.io/media/icon_hub8e78e924f485fc7b096b5b784d79d81_183359_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>会议论文</title>
      <link>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication-type/%E4%BC%9A%E8%AE%AE%E8%AE%BA%E6%96%87/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cross-domain Data Sharing Scheme Based on Federated Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication/conference-paper/2025/tase-mao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication/conference-paper/2025/tase-mao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Cross-domain data sharing involves exchanging or providing access to data between different systems or individuals, which is critical in domains such as healthcare, transportation, and data marketplaces. While blockchain technology addresses the single-point-of-failure issue inherent in cloud servers for cross-domain data sharing, existing blockchain-based methods face challenges such as complex permission management, high storage costs, and trust issues. To address these challenges, we propose a federated blockchain based cross-domain data sharing scheme that simplifies permission management by reducing the number of entities and specifying access rules, and decreases storage overhead through encrypted indexing. Our approach enhances trust by improving the ring signature algorithm to meet requirements for anonymity and accountability in sensitive data sharing. Specifically, the enhanced ring signature algorithm provides anonymous authentication and tamper-proof signatures while incorporating traceability features to balance privacy protection with security auditing. This scheme effectively resolves the challenges of privilege management, storage costs, trust crises, privacy protection, and security auditing in medical data sharing scenarios. Formal security proofs, performance analysis, and experimental results validate the scheme&amp;rsquo;s security, efficiency, and feasibility. Experimental data shows a reduction in signing time by at least 30% and a 14% decrease in verification time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./TASE-Mao.pdf&#34;&gt;Download paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SwiftGuard: Swift and Secure Attribute-Based Access Control Scalable to Cross-Domain Emergency Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication/conference-paper/2024/cscwd-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jackaugust.github.io/zh/publication/conference-paper/2024/cscwd-zhang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;As healthcare systems evolve and healthcare data grows, the need for cross-domain collaboration treatment has become more complex, necessitating fine-grained access control to enhance privacy and security. Blockchain provides a distributed trusted platform without third parties, but the current blockchain-based access control systems lack efficiency and sufficient privacy protection in cross-domain collaboration. To address these challenges, we propose SWIFTGUARD, an efficient and fine-grained access control system based on a master-slave chain to strengthen the security and privacy of cross-domain healthcare collaboration. SWIFTGUARD incorporates a zeroknowledge proof protocol for cross-domain authentication without exposing sensitive data and leverages quantitative attribute weights for efficient access control. Through game-based security proof, we demonstrate the zero knowledge and soundness of the system. Extensive experiments evaluate that SWIFTGUARD reduces the time complexity of access authorization from $O(n)$ to $O(\log n)$, with improved throughput and stable performance in cross-domain collaboration. Our comprehensive evaluation confirms that SWIFTGUARD provides a secure and efficient access control system for cross-domain healthcare collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./CSCWD-Zhang.pdf&#34;&gt;Download paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
